[♪ theme music playing]
The Manipulated
-[laughs]
-What?
-Call it off?
-Yeah.
Well. Park Taejoong
hasn't been caught yet. so I'm sure--
-Hello?
-[chuckles]
Yeah. I'll mobilize the team now.
Shit.
-It's been a blast. but we're done.
-Hang on a sec.
Why are they terminating this? Huh?
Guys like us
are only supposed to follow orders.
-What does it matter?
-That's not good enough for me.
You want to know that badly?
Yeah.
[chuckles]
All right. then. Hop in.
[engine starts]
Your car is ready. sir.
Thanks. Appreciate your help.
-Take care.
-Bye.
[Eunbi grunting softly]
Taejoong and I agreed to meet up in Seoul.
Maybe we should have gone there together.
Listen. I think
you should stay here and...
[Eunbi sighs]
[sirens approaching]
-Wait. what's going on?
-You're under arrest.
What are you doing? Wait!
-Hey! What are you doing?
-Stay still.
Stop moving!
Wait! Let me go!
Move in! Come on.
You can't do this!
Enough!
This has to be illegal!
What a fucking brat.
-Noh Yongsik.
-[groans]
You're under arrest as a suspect
in the recent murder of Assemblyman Baek.
-All right. guys.
-But you're making a mistake!
I don't know what you're talking about!
You have the right to remain silent.
and to an attorney.
Anything you say can be used
against you in a court of law.
[Eunbi] He didn't do anything wrong!
Get the fuck off of me. Detective!
[Eunbi] Papa! My dad is innocent!
[Hwang Ilguk laughs]
Papa!
[sirens wailing]
[reporters clamoring]
Let's go. let's go! Let's go!
-Get out of the way!
-[reporter] Mr. Noh!
Mr. Noh! Do you have anything to say?
[reporter] The suspect. Mr. Noh.
who murdered Assemblyman Baek Sangman.
has finally been caught
after a long pursuit.
He was recently released
after serving a 20-year sentence
for the murder of his wife.
Investigations revealed
that shortly after his release.
he began sending threatening letters
and demanding money from the assemblyman.
Furthermore. given that the perpetrator
killed a sitting member
of the National Assembly.
the police are focusing
their investigation
on whether there were any accomplices.
The Manipulated
That's all we need.
[sighs]
So why'd you do it?
[door closes]
I thought I was innocent
until proven guilty.
You're labeling me as a murderer
when I don't even know what's going on.
I swear you have the wrong person.
But didn't you send letters
to the assemblyman
asking for money
and threatening to kill him?
That wasn't me sending all those letters.
I promise
I'm telling you the truth. Detective.
I'm sorry. ma'am.
I don't care. I have to get inside.
-Please calm down.
-Get out of my way!
He's being interrogated right now.
so we can't let you in.
What's the real reason I can't?
Don't you know I'm his daughter?
-What the fuck are you doing to him?
-Stay calm.
Move out of my way!
-Let me in there!
-Stop!
[detective] Ring any bells?
Seriously?
How many times do I have to tell you?
It's the first time
I've ever seen this place.
I don't know where this is.
So how would I be able
to send those letters there?
[reporter] In the latest development
of the murder of Assemblyman Baek.
the papers used in the letters.
along with the victim's DNA.
were found in the suspect's home.
Due to these findings.
police are investigating this crime
as premeditated murder.
PROBABILITY OF BEING THE SAME INDIVIDUAL
99.9993%
So you're saying the victim's DNA
was found in my house?
Yes.
DNA MATCH REPORT
And also that my DNA was found
at the crime scene as well?
[sighs]
[scoffs]
I can't believe they went into my house.
[exhales heavily]
Eunbi.
I don't think I can help you.
What? You're leaving?
If you get appointed another lawyer.
maybe you should consider
that honesty is the best policy.
Wait. No.
Sir. my daughter is...
Eunbi is in danger.
What do I do?
-Time to go.
-Please. officers.
I've to get to my daughter right now.
-She's not safe at home by herself.
-Okay.
I have to protect her.
-Stay calm. sir.
-Don't you understand?
-Hey!
-I have to get to her!
Eunbi! [grunting]
-Hold him down.
-[yells]
Don't you understand
what kind of danger she's in?
[sighs]
Here.
Why are we moving so fast on this case?
It's open and shut.
so we might as well wrap it up quickly.
-Are you bringing in the daughter?
-Of course we are.
We found evidence that she received
a cut of the criminal proceeds.
They're in it together.
My daughter had nothing to do
with any of this!
-Oh. Scared me.
-If you dare lay even a finger on her.
I swear. I'll make all of you pay for it.
Got it?
-Shit.
-[laughing] That's funny.
-You'll make me pay?
-Hey. come on.
Back off.
-Was that a threat?
-Hey. listen. I'm sorry.
Just leave my daughter out of this.
I'll do anything.
I'm begging you.
Then confess.
We already have all the evidence.
We're both innocent.
Forget it. We'll get our answers
after we interrogate her.
Hey! If you do anything to hurt her.
I'll kill every single one
of you assholes!
You fucking hear me?
Eunbi is innocent!
[laughs]
I need a smoke.
[laughing]
Hey. Hey!
[whimpers] Eunbi. Eunbi.
[breath trembling]
GET LOST MURDERER
GO TO HELL
Eunbi.
Eunbi!
-Are you here?
-[objects clattering]
[breathing heavily]
[sighs]
Shit.
[chiming]
Bastard!
[grunts loudly]
[breathing heavily]
[door rattling]
[Eunbi crying]
[breath trembling]
[sobbing]
We truly got blindsided with all this.
This isn't your dad's fault.
You know that. right?
What does it matter?
No one will believe what we have to say.
They already decided he's guilty.
Everybody else might believe those lies.
But you... We know the truth.
What good is that?
Why is he taking the blame for all this?
Why be such an idiot?
Can't he fight back for once?
It's like he doesn't even try!
[continues crying]
What am I supposed to do?
What if my dad goes back to prison?
I can't do this again.
Listen. this all happened
because of me. so...
I'll fix it.
I'll figure something out. okay?
What are you gonna do?
No. wait.
Where are you going?
You can't leave! [sobbing]
Congratulations. Young Master.
Your 100th sculpture.
And how do you know that?
Because I've been keeping track.
For this auction.
what about holding a special exhibition?
That would be the perfect chance
to reveal yourself.
And why should I?
Arleli's genius as an artist
deserves to be praised properly.
So. the world should know
his true identity.
The name of the greatest artist
to ever live.
An Yohan. [chuckles softly]
You're right.
It's time to step out of the shadows.
And when this sculpture goes to auction.
I will outbid everyone.
You'll buy it?
No one would appreciate it as much as me.
I understand the true value of your work.
I would never give up
this beautiful sculpture.
When I die. I want it buried with me.
Do you know why I like to hold auctions?
I love to watch them panic.
I just can't get enough of it.
Seeing their desperate little faces
when they realize their fate
is in someone else's hands.
And as their bids climb higher and higher.
they start begging for their lives.
Nothing else compares to it. [laughs]
[line ringing]
[panting]
[Yohan] I thought you'd call me sooner.
Why him?
Why are you doing this?
I'm the one you want. aren't I?
I did what I had to.
I needed to get your attention somehow.
[sighs]
Let's keep innocent people
out of this. okay?
-Why don't we meet and we can settle this?
-Look at that.
I knew doing that
would force you to reach out.
-So now what?
-If you had called sooner.
your friend could have been spared.
He shouldn't be the one to suffer.
Don't you agree?
So what is it you want from me.
you fucking psycho?
All of this happened
because of your actions.
so I'll give you the chance to fix it.
[cell phone vibrating]
Open the box in front of you.
[panting]
That's the knife
that killed Assemblyman Baek.
You can take it. turn yourself in
and go back to prison
or write down the amount
you want on a blank check there.
I sincerely hope you make
the right choice and join me.
I'm trying to make this as easy
as possible.
but it's up to you.
The knife in your possession.
whose life will it end?
First. let me ask you something.
What's the reason that you're doing this?
Why do you take people--
And sculpt them to look like murderers?
That's easy.
It's because they were convenient to use.
They happened to be
where I needed them to be.
I like to think of it
as collateral damage.
Unfortunate but inevitable.
When people walk around.
sometimes they end up stepping on ants.
But do they ever feel
the need to apologize?
-Of course not.
-What's your point?
It's a simple observation.
I've also noticed something
pretty interesting.
I think before people die.
they stop fighting the inevitable
and accept fate.
I have a feeling Noh Yongsik
will prove me right today.
I get it. You win.
[laughing]
I already won this a while ago.
All I'm doing now
is cleaning up your mess.
I'm really doing you a favor.
so you should be saying thanks.
[sighs]
Hello?
Why can't he understand
when I'm being so clear?
[laughs]
Why does everyone
make things so hard? Huh?
[exhales heavily]
[breathes deeply]
Eunbi.
Papa!
-That's my little girl.
-[laughs]
Watch your step when you run. sweetheart.
Can you find me a four-leaf clover. Daddy?
Of course. darling.
Let's go find one together.
I think I know where they are.
We'll make sure to find you
the best four-leaf clover.
Do you see any?
-[buzzer blares]
-[door opens]
-[child Eunbi] Papa!
-Eunbi.
Ta-da!
Guess how many awards I got?
What's with all those scratches on you?
Did you get in a fight?
I didn't start it.
The other kids at school
kept saying you were a loser.
Even if they did.
you should've walked away.
I tried to.
but they wouldn't leave me alone.
Listen. Eunbi.
Put that down for a second.
I have to explain
something important. okay?
For me to work hard in here
and earn as much as I can for us.
I need to focus on making money.
which means I won't have
a lot of time to see you.
So you shouldn't visit me anymore.
Why?
For now. it would be best
if you forget that I exist.
Okay? And if anyone asks.
don't tell them I'm your father.
Those people will make fun of you
if you do.
Well. you can go and tell them off.
can't you?
You know what?
I'm not your papa anymore.
Papa...
Don't call me that. okay?
-From now on. you don't have a dad.
-[cries]
We don't know each other. got it?
Go.
And don't ever come back.
Papa! Papa. don't leave me!
[crying]
Papa!
ELECTRONICS REPAIR SHOP
Eunbi.
I thought we didn't know each other.
You have nowhere to go?
Oh. It's just...
Whatever.
I guess this place is yours.
I've been wanting to leave anyways.
Wait. Eunbi. Hold on.
You stay here at the store.
I'll find somewhere else.
I'll go. okay?
Sorry.
[sighs] Shit.
Are you deaf? I said I'm leaving.
so don't just walk away.
I... I'm sorry. sweetheart.
[sighs]
So...
[sniffles]
You have to pay the rent.
Make sure you have the money every month.
Enough for utilities too.
What? Don't like it?
Uh. no. that all sounds really good.
This is your house now.
so I should pay you rent.
[Eunbi exhales]
Actually. I've been itching to work again.
so paying rent won't be an issue.
even if it's not for rent--
[Hanbyeol] Eunbi. why are you
so mean to your dad?
You always said how much you missed him
while he was in prison.
[Eunbi] I don't know why I'm like this.
After seeing him again.
all I felt was anger and frustration.
That's because you love him. you know.
[scoffs] No. it's not.
[Hanbyeol] Well. I like him.
Even if he's a little weird.
Like. why does he hide his money?
[Eunbi] I know. right?
Trust me. I don't understand it either.
It always seemed strange.
but that's the way he is. I guess.
[chuckles softly]
[cries]
She kept pestering me to see you.
so I brought her in with me.
You only have ten minutes.
-I'll be back to get her.
-Okay.
I appreciate it. ma'am.
[door opens and closes]
You okay?
They're feeding you every day. right?
And those cops.
they better not be abusing you in here.
You tell me if they are.
and I'll kill them all. okay?
[laughing]
How can you be laughing?
I was thinking how I wouldn't expect
anything less from you.
[chuckles]
[laughs] Shit.
Whatever happens to me in the future.
I want you to stay out of it.
-Why?
-Just do what I say.
Don't worry about me.
[knock on door]
In my workbench.
take a look in the drawer at the bottom.
All the money in there is yours.
[knocking on door]
Coming.
What are you planning to do right now?
[sighs]
[door closes]
[reporter] Breaking news. The suspect
in Assemblyman Baek's murder case
has finally confessed.
According to the confession.
after his release from prison.
the suspect found
the assemblyman's address
via a TV interview.
and sent him threatening letters.
But after no response.
the suspect murdered him.
[Changhyuk] It's him.
Didn't he just get released?
...whether to disclose personal details
of Mr. Noh.
who committed this premeditated murder
and a conclusion is expected soon.
Mr. Noh. who had persistently
denied the crime.
began to confess
after decisive evidence emerged
and the police are now focusing
all efforts
on securing additional evidence
based on his testimony.
I have an appointment
with Detective Hwang.
[detective] To be clear. you're admitting
that you threatened Assemblyman Baek.
and when things didn't go your way.
you killed him?
[Noh Yongsik] Yes. I killed him.
Why are you making me repeat myself
over and over?
I already said I did it.
What else do you want from me?
You guys win. okay? You caught me.
You found all that evidence at my house.
So don't you have everything you need?
That's enough.
[door opens]
Detective.
[sighs]
You know what the scariest thing
in prison is?
It's the other inmates.
That's why they're always trying
to prove how dangerous they are.
They put on a facade for protection
and pretend to be someone
that they're not.
I can spot those people from a mile away.
and I'm telling you.
that man is faking it.
Hmm.
[chuckling]
Even with his confession.
you're still entertaining these theories.
It's not a theory!
It's experience.
They can't think in the long term.
They don't care.
Because of that. they'll throw
everything away in order to survive.
So what then?
What I saw in that room...
was someone lying to us.
Just to protect his family.
You think?
I'm pretty sure he admitted
to the whole thing.
I'm begging you to listen to me.
Enough of your shit.
Maybe you forgot. but he already
went to prison for murdering his wife.
All you need to do is stay in your lane
and leave the detective work
to the real authorities.
You're just a useless prison guard.
[chuckles softly]
Who the fuck does
this asshole think he is?
[exhales heavily]
[Hwang Ilguk] What? He's not the killer?
Someone's claiming
he's the one who killed Assemblyman Baek!
What the hell?
-What's this asshole doing outside?
-[officer] I've no idea.
[detective] Put down the knife!
[sighs] Bring him in.
What a surprise.
How you been?
Good work. Get the knife.
Understood. sir.
[footsteps approaching]
[cell door opening]
Let's go.
All right. Take a left up here.
Keep walking.
-Taejoong.
-[officer] Wait! Stop him.
-Hey. Keep moving!
-Wait. No!
-Taejoong!
-All right. don't make this difficult.
-Take him this way.
-I can't do this right now.
-Come on.
-Taejoong!
Don't make this harder than it has to be.
[lock clicking]
[officer] Give me your hands.
[grunts softly]
[sighs]
[Noh Yongsik] That's my little girl.
[child Eunbi] Papa!
[Noh Yongsik] Watch your step
when you run. sweetheart.
[child Eunbi] Can you find me
a four-leaf clover. Daddy?
[Noh Yongsik] Of course. darling.
Let's go find one together.
We'll make sure to find you
the best four-leaf clover.
Do you see any? Is that one?
[door opens]
[Noh Yongsik sighs]
-Eunbi.
-[gasping]
[crying]
Go.
I said go.
I don't want to see you!
-Eunbi.
-[cries]
If you like it there so much.
why bother coming out? Huh?
Is taking the blame
the only thing you know how to do?
What's wrong with you?
Why'd you confess to something
that you know you didn't do?
-Eunbi.
-[sobbing]
I don't understand why you had to
go and turn yourself in like that.
I'm sorry.
I can't keep watching you leave
over and over again.
-[both crying]
-I'm so sorry.
I promise I'll never leave you again.
I'm sorry.
I'm right here.
No. no. Listen to me.
He showed up last night with the knife...
He turned himself in
so we weren't legally allowed
to detain Noh Yongsik
longer than 48 hours.
What?
What do you mean
you'll handle it yourself?
Hello? Mr. An?
Shit! I'm screwed. aren't I?
[exhales]
You. Leave.
-What?
-Get the fuck out.
What made you do this?
I gave you every opportunity
to make the smart choice. didn't I?
If you'd waited one more day.
Noh Yongsik would've killed himself.
You should've held out.
Why would you run head first
into your own death sentence?
Tell me.
[sighs]
No one ever answers me
when I'm speaking to them.
and I'm sick of it!
You don't get it.
You're asking the wrong questions.
So there's no use in giving you an answer.
It's funny...
I was always so curious.
I kept wondering who the fuck you were
and why you were doing
such horrible things to me.
But looking at you now. I realize...
you're nothing but a kid.
[Yohan sighs deeply]
I'm getting bored. so I think we're done.
This is what you want?
[scoffs] You can die. then.
What happens after an escapee is caught?
[Hanhee] We take custody
as according to procedure.
And after that?
There's usually another trial
for the criminal offenses.
But since he's already sentenced to life.
I'm not sure they can do much more.
Let's kill him. then.
What?
You can choose how you'd like to do it.
but just make sure you take care of it.
Okay. I understand.
2802. Park Taejoong.
I'm here to transport him.
Okay. I'll let them know you're here.
Park Taejoong.
Stand up so we can cuff you.
You're going back to prison.
-Welcome back. sir.
-Yeah.
[Cheolhwan sighs]
I told you he was scheduled
to be interrogated more.
so why are you here?
You came earlier than expected.
If you need to question him. you can
just apply for visitation at the prison.
This is revenge for earlier?
I have to follow standard procedure.
I'm only a prison guard. remember?
You prison guards love your procedures.
don't you?
[laughs]
Okay.
Fine.
Get out of here.
Come on.
-Let's go.
-[engine starts]
EMERGENCY TRANSFER
MINISTRY OF JUSTICE
[Cheolhwan exhales]
We've had to upgrade
a lot of things because of you.
The ventilation ducts.
we installed wire mesh.
There's increased security
for visitation. too.
[chuckles softly]
Thanks to you. we're better off now.
Hey...
The items in that locker...
Why give them to me?
Those items are the key to the truth.
And you were the only one from the prison
that I felt I could give it to.
You have a lot of faith.
What if I had thrown those things away?
Come on.
You don't even throw away sick plants.
I heard you turned yourself in.
Does that mean you've given up now?
[sighs]
I don't know.
Actually. you're right. I'm done running.
You know...
I don't regret
turning myself in to save him.
[scoffs]
Even back then...
I'm not sure I ever really understood you
and I don't think I ever will.
Hey. let's take a break
at the next rest stop.
[driver] Understood. sir.
GOYANG REST STOP
Since we're stopping.
I might as well use the bathroom.
[engine starts]
Hands.
[lock clicking]
From this point on.
a new road is ahead of you.
What are you doing?
Get a move on.
Come on.
If you go that way.
a van will be waiting for you.
I wish I could do more.
I truly do.
But I have no real power.
I'm only a prison guard.
So this is the best I can do for you.
Go on.
Oh. and Taejoong.
next time. instead of prison.
I hope we meet somewhere better.
Park Taejoong.
I needed to prove my innocence.
So I'm at the culprit's location now.
Park Taejoong's whereabouts
have been found.
BUSAN TERMINAL AREA B
[Sangrak] I was just
following orders from above.
Her name's So Hyeonjeong.
She's the next victim.
They'll begin sculpting with her soon.
We're creating evidence to use.
When a client commits murder. they look
for a victim to be the scapegoat.
[Hanhee] Okay. I understand.
Consider it done.
Don't worry about 2802.
I'll make sure he ends up dead.
What have I gotten myself into?
Taejoong!
[sighs]
Hurry. over here!
Let's get moving.
You need an escape?
Get in.
Let's get out of here.
Why is he alone?
Why isn't 2802 with you?
Because. Warden.
after thinking about it.
I made a change of plans.
Are you fucking crazy?
Have you lost your mind?
You're gonna be disciplined for this.
[groans]
Go ahead. Discipline me?
I've called Internal Affairs
and I'll tell them everything.
But what about you?
Will you admit
you were gonna kill him for money?
You stupid son of a bitch!
Where's all this coming from?
-This isn't like you.
-Shut up!
You shut your mouth.
[reporter] Now. with the latest story
from the art world.
Arleli. the famous and mysterious artist.
has announced their decision
to finally reveal themselves
to the public for the first time.
Sources tell me that this will happen
at a special exhibition
unveiling the 100th sculpture.
Additionally. this piece will be
up for auction at the event.
stirring excitement in Korea's art scene.
-What's all this?
-Here. [grunts]
I wasn't sure what we needed.
so I grabbed whatever I could.
Let's do it.
That son of a bitch
needs to be taught a lesson.
Just think of this as divine intervention.
[applause]
The Manipulated